Preliminary Inventory to the Conference for Conclusion and Signature of Treaty of Peace with Japan (1951: San Francisco) Records, 1951
Hoover Institution Archives
Conference for Conclusion and Signature of Treaty of Peace with Japan (1951: San Francisco) Records,
XX336
Conference for Conclusion and Signature of Treaty of Peace with Japan (1951: San Francisco)
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Bulletins, press releases, minutes of meetings, agenda, rosters of participants, texts of the treaty, protocols, and statements of delegates.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Peace; World War, 1939-1945--Japan; Japan
Container List
- San Francisco, 1951 September 4-8
  - List of documents issued, 1951 September 8 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Residence and office directory (Folder 2)
  - Department of State publication 4330. Far Eastern series, 49. Draft treaty of peace with Japan (Folder 3)
  - Information bulletin, nos. 1-14 (Folder 4)
  - Document nos. 1-9, 9 supplements, 10-21 (#5 missing) (Folder 5)
  - Order of the day, nos. 1-4 (Folder 6)
  - Press release, nos. 1-15, 15A, 16-18 (Folder 7)
  - Netherlands delegation to Japanese Peace Conference (Folder 8)
  - Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Company. Press release, 1951 September 1 (Folder 9)
  - Department of State. Press release, 1951 September 1. In resigning of tripartite treaty by Australia, New Zealand and the United States (Folder 10)
  - Department of State. Press release, nos. 764, 765 (Folder 11)
  - The Black Cat. San Francisco, Japanese Peace Treaty Conference. Special edition, 1951 September 3 (Folder 12)
  - Newsweek. Press release, 1951 September 5. Regarding Dulles and Japanese on Atlantic pact basis (Folder 13)
  - List of press, radio, television, newsreel, and still photographs accredited to cover the Japanese Peace Conference, San Francisco, 1951 September (Folder 14)
  - Letter and speech of Governor Warren (Folder 15)